<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf8'?>
<objects><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 02:41:49</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/19/19hawks/</browser_link><header>Hawk Cam welcomes new hawk, returns with educational focus</header><teaser>After its shutdown last August, the Hawk Cam returned last week with Bobby's new mate and an educational focus. </teaser><images><item><width>592</width><content_id>52974</content_id><credit>via Livestream</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/90/21/90219dd9af2d406d6920de1dc375bdf7.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/19/19hawks/03-19-hawks.png</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/4d/7f/4d7f2e0e7dc8f870a1acf0a2d55ff67a.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/00/86/00861cb3e5e2c0a598d519f2e658b39f.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/19/19hawks/</browser_link><height>332</height></item></images><id>52974</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/7b/a4/7ba41ebab3a31d97c2fc2e74d9e72be4.jpg</thumb><byline>Eric Benson</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The Hawk Cam at Bobst Library officially returned for its second season last Monday. Perched on the 12th floor of Bobst, the live webcam featured on The New York Times website is now focused on two red-tailed hawks, Bobby and Rosie, who call the ledge outside of NYU President John Sexton's window home.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hawk Cam was first launched last spring to stream live footage of Bobby and his mate Violet, who died in late December due to heart complications. Millions of online viewers watched the couple birth and raise their young up until the cameras shutdown after both hawks flew away in August last year.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;This year, NYU spokesman John Beckman has proposed a more expansive educational role of the Hawk Cam by partnering with the New York City Audubon, a grassroots community that works to protect wild birds in New York City.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"As an educational institution, we thought it would be beneficial if there was more of an educational aspect to the Hawk Cam from the outset than was the case last year," Beckman said. "New York City Audubon is in a great position to help educate us all about hawks, about how to think about wildlife in general and in urban settings and to give us insights into what's going on in the nest."&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Featured on the City Room section of The Times website, Hawk Cam sports both its own blog and chatroom to accompany the live feed.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Times reporter Emily Rueb, who updates the blog, expressed City Room's anticipation for this new season of bird watching.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"We are excited to welcome back the Hawk Cam feature that built a lively community last year," Rueb said. "A partnership with New York City Audubon will also increase the educational components of the feature this season with a new question and answer session with readers. The camera will remain in place as long as the birds do."&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Susan Elbin, ornithologist and New York City Audubon director of conservation and science, has worked in the field of behavioral ecology and conservation for more than 25 years and is currently answering readers' questions regarding the hawks.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"Red-tailed hawks typically build their nests in trees," Elbin said on the City Room website. "But when trees are not available, they will build nests on cliff faces. In New York City, our cliff faces are tall buildings with window ledges and setbacks." &amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;In addition to expert commentary, Hawk Cam may soon be scheduled to partner with local schools for further educational opportunities.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"As to working it into educational programs, that would be up to NYU faculty to decide for themselves, though it would be great," Beckman said. "We may look to see whether there is an opportunity to work with local schools in some way, but that's very preliminary."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;LSP freshman Justyna Michaelik said the cam is a great way to interact with nature without harming it.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"All in all, I think it's really cool how they set up the hawk cam since it gives us a view into the life of animals that we don't see on a day to day basis," Michaelik said.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:35:12</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 01:31:36</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/19/19kony/</browser_link><header>Students, faculty respond to Kony 2012 video</header><teaser>NYU and colleges nationwide respond to Kony 2012 with on-campus screenings and activism.  </teaser><images /><id>52975</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline>Julie DeVito</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;With the rise of the viral video Kony 2012, nonprofit organization Invisible Children has gained the support of students and faculty, resulting in a wave of on-campus screenings and activism at NYU and other universities nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Invisible Children released the video as part of an effort to gain awareness about Joseph Kony, leader of the Lord's Resistance Army in Uganda. The video calls for the arrest of the LRA leaders who have abducted more than 30,000 children for use as soldiers or the officers' sex slaves.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The 29-minute video has been viewed over 70 million times and declared by Mashable, the largest online new site that specifically covers social media, as the most viral internet video in history.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Danah Boyd, Steinhardt professor of Media, Culture and Communication, said teenagers and college students watching the video see how Jason Russell explains the situation to his child and realize they, too, can explain the situation to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"The film is powerful, but it also models how to spread information," Boyd said. "Young people feel like they did something by getting a celebrity to pay attention to a cause. A celebrity feels like they've done some by talking about the cause to a wide audience. And, voila, Invisible Children taps into the attention economy to get their message out."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Child (not) Soldier at NYU will be holding a screening of Kony 2012 on campus this Wednesday. The club has also collaborated with organizations including NYU Pi Delta Psi Fraternity's Talent Show, Crepeaway and NYU Chinese Mei Society to raise money and awareness to help the children in Uganda.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"Our ultimate goal is to strengthen the movement against the LRA and stop this heinous conflict," Venuis Choi, CAS junior and vice president of the club, said. "We believe that making our voices louder and expressing our concerns will encourage the government and others in power to act."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Gallatin freshman Jacob Avnier said the video has spread awareness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"I did research on [the Invisible Children] project, though, and not all the numbers add up," Avnier said. "The guy just got arrested for masturbating in public, and I think he's kind of crazy, but the video itself is good to start to creating awareness."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The video encourages participation in an event on April 20 called "Cover the Night," when groups across the country are encouraged to gather to cover the streets with posters, stickers and signs of Joseph Kony.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The Center for Global Justice at Regent University School of Law is hosting a conference later this month. It will invite speakers to discuss issues of human trafficking, the protection of children and religious freedom on both a global and domestic scale.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"Ending human rights violations in our world today can often be most effectively accomplished through the efforts of media to raise awareness, and the efforts of those skilled in the law and other related disciplines to provide the necessary solutions and protections," Ashleigh Chapman, professor and administrative director of law at Regent's Center for Global Justice, Human Rights and the Rule of Law, said.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;University of Redlands student Stephen Bachner said the goal of stopping social injustice is personal. Bachner, who is the president of the Invisible Children club at his school, is the grandson of a Holocaust survivor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"I could not stand idly by and watch hundreds of thousands of innocent people brutally murdered, kidnapped and forced to commit atrocities, or become displaced because of the conflict," Bachner said. "As a human being, I have a moral obligation to ensure atrocities like the ones occurring in Africa are stopped."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:31:36</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-09 02:14:44</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/09/09obrien1/</browser_link><header>Remembering a friend and colleague</header><teaser>Tony Chiaravelotti, a CAS advisor, reflects on the life and achievements of beloved friend, Dermot O'Brien, who passed away on March 3.</teaser><images /><id>52953</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline>Tony Chiaravelotti</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Dermot O'Brien passed away on Saturday, March 3, at the age of 51. He held a doctorate in politics from NYU, and he taught courses here for many years in the politics department in the Graduate School of Arts and Science and the College of Arts and Science and in the School of Continuing and Professional Studies. He was also the director of academic support and a full-time academic adviser to a great many students in the CAS Advising Center for the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Dr. O'Brien was not one for pretense, titles or formality, so he was known to us all as Dermot. He was tall, thin and spoke with a deep baritone voice. He was equal parts New Yorker and Dubliner, and he was more than the sum of his parts. He spoke confidently and liked to cut to the chase. He believed brevity was the soul of wit. A good staff meeting was a short one — the shorter the better. He often used humor to make his points, and it was not hard to know where he stood on any topic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;He cared about his students and tried to steer them toward exceptional learning opportunities. Whenever he could, he took time to get to know his students and determine their interests, even if they did not yet know. His students gave him glowing reviews both for his teaching and his advising. In the classroom, he had a talent for distilling the ideas of complex thinkers like Nietzsche and post-modern political thinkers into terms that vividly captured their essences. He made complex ideas clear and understandable to students. He stressed the importance of excellent writing and fostered it during his office hours. As an adviser, he worked hard to keep his students well-informed and to challenge their notions about what they could do with their liberal arts degrees. ("What can't you do?" was his view). He steered them in directions he thought would give them an edge. He enjoyed promoting the Freshman Honors Seminar courses and would do whatever he could to get all of his freshmen into those seminars. He sat on committees within the dean's office and used his teaching experience to help design programs that would benefit freshmen. He was active on the student readmission committee — he believed in giving students a second chance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;He was the father of two sons, and he enjoyed bringing them to the office every so often, where they would sit at their father's desk and imagine what it was like to be him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;He was a soccer fan, of course, and he loved the Irish rugby team as well. He was a devoted but frustrated fan of the New York Mets, and he loved American football, particularly the Dallas Cowboys. He was an intellectual well-read in the fields of politics and philosophy — his areas of expertise. But he kept up with the latest literary works and intellectual trends. He loved living in New York, working in Manhattan and then going home to Brooklyn, the best of all possible worlds. He was a proud father of two sons, Aidan and Jack, who adore him (and he them).&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;As a writer, he was steeped in the verses and rhetorical flourishes of the Irish and Anglo-American canon. His turns of phrase would have made one of his literary heroes, Eugene O'Neil, proud. He leaves behind a number of works in progress, including several plays, manuscripts and essays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Not just a person of the academy, he loved popular culture equally well. He made a successful appearance on the TV trivia program "Cash Cab," leading his fellow passengers to a victory with his extensive knowledge and retention of cultural and historical minutiae. He also was the regular host of a weekly trivia game, which he designed and ran at his local watering hole in Greenpoint, Brooklyn. He was a voracious lover of life, his kids, his family, opera, theater, sports and great works of literature. He was fond of good eating. Always quite the chef, he would bring his culinary creations to the office for lunch. He fully embraced his inner Sir John Falstaff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;As a colleague, he was funny and spirited. He held opinions on everything ranging from the profound to the mundane. In education, the liberal arts were supreme; regarding the office brew, he would expound on the evils of flavored coffee. He was, after all, a purist in most things. Almost daily, he found new ways to be funny in his observations. His office on the ninth floor of the Silver Center was the one nearest to the daily laughter of student workers and was usually its source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Dermot died suddenly and unexpectedly in his sleep last weekend. To all who knew and loved him (his children, family, friends, students, colleagues), he had a lot more left to give and he will be dearly missed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A memorial service is being planned here on campus for Friday, March 23 at 3:00 p.m. on the first floor of Silver Center.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-09 12:06:55</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-08 10:55:07</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/09/09obrien2/</browser_link><header>Student reflections</header><teaser>NYU students share memories of their former advisor and mentor. </teaser><images /><id>52939</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline /><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"I met Dr. Dermot O'Brien four years ago at my freshman CAS summer orientation. He popped into our group session and introduced himself as our advisor, told us he'd make sure we had an amazing academic career at NYU, chuckled, waved and said, 'Cheers!' During our first session in Fall 2008, Dermot beckoned me into his office with a smile and, looking quickly through my file, exclaimed, 'You're from Florida?! It's so sunny and wonderful there. I'm so jealous. Call me Dermot.' ... Always available, always supportive, always cheery — Dermot just cared. And he cared about the well-being of all students at NYU, not just those he officially advised. Whenever a friend or classmate had an advising concern, I always recommended they walk in to see Dermot because he was the absolute best. He guided me through my entire NYU career and has impacted the direction of my future."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;— Jessica Philips, senior&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"I loved walking into his office and seeing his pictures of Ireland and of his family. He was a big part of why I decided to study abroad — I am studying in NYU London at the moment — because he really encouraged me to take advantage of what NYU was offering in its abroad sites. ... The only time when his advice wasn't exactly the best was when he advised me to take Nat Sci II: Energy and the Environment with Professor Jordon because he was also going to take the class. Halfway through the semester I realized that Dermot was no longer showing up to the classes. After the semester was over and I went to Dermot to ask why he stopped going to the class, [and] he said, 'Because it was bloody difficult.' We laughed even though I ended up with a C in the class (because it was bloody difficult), and he assured me that I could make up my GPA with other classes."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;— Erica Cheung, junior&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"I had a really bad semester and I was going to be put on academic probation for failing two classes, but he sorted it out really fast. I told him about my plan to skip a semester and he got right on board with it and told me it was totally normal. I missed my last advising session with him, and I feel really bad about that. He was very wise. I got the feeling that he had seen it all, and no matter what I told him, there would be no judgment."&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;— Paul Brown, junior&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"In a big university in a big city, there are very few people who will take the time to talk to you for even a second. Dermot would not only talk to you, he would take a step back with you and look at whatever issue or concern you might have been having. After five minutes, not only would you realize that your problem was not as impassible as you might have thought, but that it was actually funny, and that the two of you could laugh about it together. It is very hard to be caring and hilarious at the same time, and he somehow managed it. No one would leave that office without a smile. ... He was a good man who brought only good things into the world."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;— Mark Pierce, junior&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-08 10:40:10</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-08 11:54:20</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/08/08brabeck/</browser_link><header>New commission aims to raise teaching standards</header><teaser>The Council for the accreditation of Educator Preparation announced yesterday that Steinhardt dean Mary Brabeck has been names to the Commission on Standards and Performance Reporting.</teaser><images><item><width>333</width><content_id>52904</content_id><credit>via steinhardt.nyu.edu</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/b9/36/b936599504bbf747e963791a0a118653.jpg</t800_url><caption>Steinhardt dean Mary Brabeck</caption><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/8/08brabeck/03-08-brabeck.jpeg</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/39/dc/39dcf18eb8a5ff0075a0c0a06844df01.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/bf/b2/bfb245e3d6b0e81b72e96a70fa8de8da.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/08/08brabeck/</browser_link><height>500</height></item></images><id>52904</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/54/a6/54a6322d5c9c0158708132916f27b72d.jpg</thumb><byline>Wali Mbekani</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Steinhardt dean Mary Brabeck has been appointed along with 31 others to serve on the Commission on Standards and Performance Reporting, a national commission that was recently founded to raise accreditation standards in educator preparation.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The commission was created by the Council for the Accreditation of Educator Preparation — a national council that accredits elementary and secondary school teachers after training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;CAEP president James Cibulka said the council established the commission because it wanted to set new standards to guide its accreditation programs. They will recruit a wide range of stakeholders, critics and teachers to focus on the need of preK to 12 schools.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"We're glad Dean Brabeck will be a member," Cibulka said. "I'm sure she will bring much leadership. It's a very distinguished group, and she'll be an important educator."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;To access teacher preparation, Brabeck said the commission will focus on the inputs and outputs of education training defined by their performance as teachers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Today, there is a great emphasis on output," she said. "The focus is on how to get the best outcomes."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;According to Brabeck, the positive outcomes may reflect upon the number of prospective teachers who pass the licensure exam, and their pass rate on exit exams. The programs also analyze the manner and subject areas that teachers can educate. The assessment includes a numerical ranking that represents how the teachers are doing their jobs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;Stephanie Seaman, a junior at California Polytechnic State University San Luis Obispo and an aspiring teacher, said she would not mind working harder to be an educator. &amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"I think it's a really good idea because I know teachers need to be more educators in order to teach the amount of students," she said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s4"&gt;Midtown resident Nancy Shapiro, 49, has a daughter who is in the eighth grade. She said she regrets she only had a handful of great teachers when she went to school and hopes her daughter will have a better experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"I think it's great to have a higher standard for teachers," Shapiro said. "I think the benefits will be tremendous. The higher the teacher standard, the better potential a student will have."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;As a member of the commission, Brabeck will question whether educator preparation programs measure the effectiveness of a teacher and will determine what outcome measures will define teacher programs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"I look forward to the opportunity to shape standards for the preparation program," she said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;Cibulka said the commission will first meet in May and will release a report on their findings in 2013.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-08 04:30:05</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-07 03:55:29</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/07/07pipe/</browser_link><header>New natural gas pipe linking New Jersey and Manhattan stirs controversy</header><teaser>Angry residents are uncomfortable with Spectra Energy Corps decision to expand their natural gas pipeline system from Linden, New Jersey to the lower west side of Manhattan.</teaser><images /><id>52876</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline>Tatiana Baez</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="layoutArea"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to the high demand&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;for natural gas, Spectra energy Corps&lt;br /&gt;plans to expand their natural gas&lt;br /&gt;pipeline system from Linden, N.J., to&lt;br /&gt;the lower west side of Manhattan.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But before Spectra can begin con-&lt;br /&gt;struction, several groups — includ-&lt;br /&gt;ing the New York State Department&lt;br /&gt;of environmental Conservation —&lt;br /&gt;must approve the project. While&lt;br /&gt;it fulfills the Hudson River Park&lt;br /&gt;Trust's requirements, neither group&lt;br /&gt;can reach a consensus without the&lt;br /&gt;approval of the Federal energy Regulatory Commission.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proposal has sparked controversy among Manhattan residents who&lt;br /&gt;fear that the pipe could raise chances&lt;br /&gt;of a burst like the recent 2010 gas&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;pipeline explosion in San Bruno, Calif., that resulted in eight deaths and&lt;br /&gt;the destruction of 38 homes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I've heard about pipeline accidents in the city and other towns&lt;br /&gt;across the U.S. before and it's alarm-&lt;br /&gt;ing," said Greenwich Village resident&lt;br /&gt;Maria Sanchez.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To allay these fears, Spectra plans&lt;br /&gt;to construct a corrosion-resistant,&lt;br /&gt;high-grade carbon steel pipe over&lt;br /&gt;30 inches in diameter, with fre-&lt;br /&gt;quent x-ray inspections during&lt;br /&gt;construction. It assures that it will&lt;br /&gt;be one of the safest pipelines in&lt;br /&gt;the U.S.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Marylee Hanley, a&lt;br /&gt;representative from Spectra, the&lt;br /&gt;pipeline would be installed over&lt;br /&gt;140 feet deep through bedrock in&lt;br /&gt;certain areas and operated at a pres&lt;/span&gt;sure ... hydrostatically tested for&lt;br /&gt;nearly twice this amount of pres-&lt;br /&gt;sure ... [and] will meet or exceed all&lt;br /&gt;federal safety requirements."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hanley also praised possible benefits&lt;br /&gt;of the pipeline.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The project will bring new supplies&lt;br /&gt;of clean, domestic natural gas to New&lt;br /&gt;York City and the region, creating&lt;br /&gt;thousands of local jobs, improving the&lt;br /&gt;reliability and stability of supplies and&lt;br /&gt;lowering energy costs by hundreds of&lt;br /&gt;millions of dollars," she said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final decision for the project&lt;br /&gt;will come once the Final environ-&lt;br /&gt;mental Impact Statement is re-&lt;br /&gt;leased, and all involved bodies can&lt;br /&gt;reach a consensus.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-07 03:55:29</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-07 03:54:31</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/07/07app/</browser_link><header>Common App to launch fourth-generation of website</header><teaser>Common Application, Inc. will launch its fourth-generation version in the summer of 2013.  </teaser><images><item><width>2000</width><content_id>52875</content_id><credit>Jonathan Tan</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/26/5b/265b4d6a8b14909e3578e7179427bfc1.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/7/07app/03-07-app.JPG</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/25/e7/25e7dc98b556b2c990ea2a263a5dca2a.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/ee/7d/ee7d640a654f72d2d5655475e99be19d.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/07/07app/</browser_link><height>1328</height></item></images><id>52875</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/3d/5c/3d5c28fd6b82b41c6bc9de8cb8776eec.jpg</thumb><byline>Michelle Lee</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="layoutArea"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;CommonaApp.org is scheduled to&lt;br /&gt;launch the fourth-generation version&lt;br /&gt;of its site in the summer of 2013.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to incorporating a more&lt;br /&gt;simplified and modern interface, the&lt;br /&gt;new site will provide for a smoother&lt;br /&gt;application experience to accommo-&lt;br /&gt;date the growing number of applicants&lt;br /&gt;expected in the coming decade.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year, nearly 675,000 appli-&lt;br /&gt;cants submitted over two million ap-&lt;br /&gt;plications. That number is expected&lt;br /&gt;to increase dramatically over the&lt;br /&gt;next few years, according to Rob Kil-&lt;br /&gt;lion, executive director of Common&lt;br /&gt;Application, Inc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Our current system handles our cur-&lt;br /&gt;rent volume quite well, but it was not&lt;br /&gt;meant to handle the kinds of increases&lt;br /&gt;we're projecting," Killion said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 37-year-old system is undergoing&lt;br /&gt;a two-year revamp which could cost up&lt;br /&gt;to $8 million, according to BeginCol-&lt;br /&gt;lege.com.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several new features are expected, in&lt;/span&gt;cluding elimination of the print appli-&lt;br /&gt;cation, plagiarism-detection software&lt;br /&gt;and an iPad-friendly version. Students&lt;br /&gt;may be able to send online inquiries&lt;br /&gt;directly to college counselors and re-&lt;br /&gt;ceive window prompts that point er-&lt;br /&gt;rors in their application. But no final&lt;br /&gt;decisions have been made regarding&lt;br /&gt;the changes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Caleb Yoon, a senior at Loomis Chaf-&lt;br /&gt;fee High School in Connecticut, was&lt;br /&gt;concerned about CommonApp's cur-&lt;br /&gt;rent layout.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The website presented itself as po-&lt;br /&gt;tentially unfriendly and intimidating,"&lt;br /&gt;he said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAS freshman eunice Lau said Com-&lt;br /&gt;monApp could have been more help-&lt;br /&gt;ful in tracking to-do lists.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"More often than not, I found myself&lt;br /&gt;clicking around to see what I still need-&lt;br /&gt;ed to do," Lau said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linda Noll, a former college counselor&lt;br /&gt;at Miss Porter's School in Connecticut,&lt;br /&gt;hopes CommonApp will not interfere&lt;br /&gt;with the universities' consideration of&lt;br /&gt;applicants after the website's facelift.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;CommonApp.org will soon&lt;br /&gt;have a more modern interface.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I hope the [increased] use of Com-&lt;br /&gt;mon Application doesn't lead to col-&lt;br /&gt;leges relying on test scores and GPAs to&lt;br /&gt;determine whether or not a student is&lt;br /&gt;a good fit for their school," Noll said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Killion sees the site's makeover as a&lt;br /&gt;chance to give CommonApp.org the&lt;br /&gt;new look it has needed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Since we are building a new sys-&lt;br /&gt;tem, we're also taking the opportuni-&lt;br /&gt;ty to freshen up the user interface —&lt;br /&gt;but that's just the icing on the cake,"&lt;br /&gt;Killion said.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-07 03:54:31</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-08 03:10:17</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/07/07bridges/</browser_link><header>Tisch alum receives Academy for costume design</header><teaser>Tisch alum Mark Bridges received an Academy Award for Best Costume Design. </teaser><images /><id>52873</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline>Kayana Jean-philippe</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Tisch alumnus Mark Bridges won an Academy Award for Best Costume Design for his intricate designs and styles based on the 1920s in his work for "The Artist."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;In an interview with CNN last month, Bridges said he tried to tell the story of the movie through textures, as the movie did not have colors to do so.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"It became a story of textures telling the story," he said. "I go out and try to figure out what language of clothing are we making this story."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;After studying for three years at&amp;#160; Tisch and graduating in 1987, Bridges worked as an assistant costume designer on the film "Married to the Mob" in 1988. He has over a decade of experience in costume design, dressing renowned celebrities including Nicole Kidman, John Travolta, Eminem and Johnny Depp.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;NYU's Tony award-winning chair of design Susan Hilferty reflected on Bridges' career as a costume designer.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"He pays great attention to character while maintaining an exceptional sense of the whole story," Hilferty said. "It is very exciting for the entire NYU-Tisch Design community to see his work honored with an Oscar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;Kristen Kopp, a third-year graduate student in costume design, had the opportunity to work with Bridges on two feature films before attending NYU.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Mark was incredibly enthusiastic and encouraging as I applied to NYU," Kopp said. "He's committed to education, and I would not be here at NYU if it were not for his mentorship."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Tisch sophomore Dara Gray, who works in production and costume design for student films on campus, said it was nice to see an NYU alumnus get recognized for his work.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Set builders, make-up artists, art directors and costume designers rarely get the recognition they deserve for their work in films," Gray said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;Fellow Tisch alumna Constance Hoffman, who has returned to NYU to teach costume design, said she was thrilled that Bridges has been acknowledged for this talent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s4"&gt;"This award serves as a huge encouragement to all of our students and alumni, as well as to the faculty of the Department of Design for Stage and Film, who work so passionately to guide the young designers who enter our program," she said.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-07 03:52:09</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-07 03:56:00</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/07/07digital/</browser_link><header>Stern to add new marketing program</header><teaser>Stern School of Business announced that it will welcome a new MBA program in digital marketing next fall. </teaser><images /><id>52874</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline>Michelle Lee</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late February of this year,&lt;br /&gt;the Stern School of Business an-&lt;br /&gt;nounced that it will welcome a new&lt;br /&gt;Master of Business Administration&lt;br /&gt;program in digital marketing start-&lt;br /&gt;ing in the fall of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="layoutArea"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The specialized program consists&lt;br /&gt;of courses related to information&lt;br /&gt;systems and marketing, with a cur-&lt;br /&gt;riculum pertinent to today's devel-&lt;br /&gt;oping digital marketing field.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The program will offer courses&lt;br /&gt;from several Stern departments,&lt;br /&gt;including information, operations&lt;br /&gt;and management sciences and&lt;br /&gt;marketing. Students specializing&lt;br /&gt;in digital marketing will be able to&lt;br /&gt;take up to six credits in approved&lt;br /&gt;Stern departments. In addition,&lt;br /&gt;some classes offered through the&lt;br /&gt;program — including Social Media&lt;br /&gt;for Brand Management, New Me-&lt;br /&gt;dia in Marketing and Information&lt;br /&gt;Privacy Law — will be based in the&lt;br /&gt;NYU School of Law.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vasant Dhar, director of&lt;br /&gt;Stern's Center for Digital&lt;br /&gt;economy Research, said&lt;br /&gt;the program reflects a cur-&lt;br /&gt;rent trend in marketing&lt;br /&gt;and information systems.&lt;br /&gt;Companies are now look-&lt;br /&gt;ing for students with con-&lt;br /&gt;crete digital marketing&lt;br /&gt;skills, and the new program is intended to make&lt;br /&gt;students more competitive&lt;br /&gt;in the job market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not Stern's first&lt;br /&gt;foray into digital marketing.&lt;br /&gt;The school has had a Digital&lt;br /&gt;economy Initiative for more&lt;br /&gt;than 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Norman White, professor&lt;br /&gt;of design and development&lt;br /&gt;for web and mobile apps,&lt;br /&gt;said the new program will&lt;br /&gt;provide a necessary focus on&lt;br /&gt;the impacts the digital field&lt;br /&gt;has had on marketing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The new data being gener-&lt;br /&gt;ated have opened up a num-&lt;br /&gt;ber of research questions&lt;br /&gt;which Stern researchers have&lt;br /&gt;strong capabilities to investi-&lt;br /&gt;gate," he said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="column"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Claudia Perlich, the chief&lt;br /&gt;scientist of an online display&lt;br /&gt;advertising company, pro-&lt;br /&gt;jected that digital marketing&lt;br /&gt;will undergo a revolution.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Marketing can no longer&lt;br /&gt;hide behind arbitrary seg-&lt;br /&gt;ments of target groups but&lt;br /&gt;will have to embrace the hard&lt;br /&gt;sciences of letting the data&lt;br /&gt;speak," Perlich said. "The&lt;br /&gt;new generation of people&lt;br /&gt;working in this area need the&lt;br /&gt;tools to walk that walk."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After concentrating on&lt;br /&gt;strategy and marketing,&lt;br /&gt;second-year MBA student&lt;br /&gt;Juston Payne plans to pur-&lt;br /&gt;sue the digital marketing&lt;br /&gt;specialization.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"[It] provides a strategic and&lt;br /&gt;analytical toolbox that is necessary for building inventive,&lt;br /&gt;effective and quantifiable&lt;br /&gt;programs," Payne said. "I currently use these skills in my&lt;br /&gt;position at Foursquare."&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-07 03:47:47</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-13 03:17:33</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/06/06women/</browser_link><header>Women filmmakers discuss experience in industry</header><teaser>Arthur L. Carter Journalism Institute hosted a panel discussion about filmmaking industry.</teaser><images><item><width>3980</width><content_id>52837</content_id><credit>Jonathan Tan</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/ec/3b/ec3be7bbc3dee9f9b2d526f0a93f6137.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/6/06women/03-06-women-jonathan-tan.JPG</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/51/69/5169eeded0521642297f6e6cb6352353.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/1f/db/1fdb4a2e0a5c2220c29e430060da2586.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/06/06women/</browser_link><height>2600</height></item></images><id>52837</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/ac/46/ac464d4b0cef7cac9e00f7022e233474.jpg</thumb><byline>Melissa Rodriguez</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Female filmmakers gathered at the Arthur L. Carter Journalism Institute at NYU last night to discuss various topics in documentary filmmaking including obstacles, activism and the role of social media. New York Women in Film and Television, an organization dedicated to the progression of women's success in film, hosted the event.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;The speakers on the panel included Heidi Ewing, producer of "Detropia," which premiered at the 2012 Sundance Film Festival; Rachel Libert, director and co-producer of "Semper Fi: Always Faithful," a film that premiered at the 2011 Tribeca Film Festival; Jenifer McShane, producer of "Mothers of Bedford"; Kendall Nelson, director and producer of "The Greater Good"&amp;#160; and moderator Paola Freccero, a New York-based film industry executive.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;NYWIFT executive director Terry Lawler organized the majority of the event for filmmakers and those who aspire to work in the industry.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"We hope that having these really excellent filmmakers, who have made these successful and controversial documentaries talk about their success, will help people move forward in their careers and give them some ideas on what to do next," she said.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;Ewing began the discussion by speaking of the challenging and rewarding aspects of the filmmaking industry.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"There is no free ride in filmmaking," she said. "In production I have needed to get rid of a lot of my content in order to shape the final piece." &amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;Nelson discussed the challenges she faced in the distribution of her film, which chronicles families whose lives have been affected by vaccination.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"Thank God I didn't think about distribution before I made the film, because selling it to television was very hard because TV is funded by pharmaceuticals," Nelson said. "When you have a certain [controversial] topic, you will have a problem in distribution."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;McShane added that filmmakers need to recognize the importance of having patience when they face challenges.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;"Persistence is really the key to hanging in there," she said.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Attendee Angelina Caccinerio, owner of her own Canadian production company, said the panel provided a unique window into the community of female filmmakers.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s4"&gt;"I think the filmmakers really shared a lot about their processes and methods," Cacciniero said. "There are a lot of women here who are making documentaries right now and [this] helped them to say it is okay if they have doubts."&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-06 03:48:43</published></article></objects>