<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf8'?>
<objects><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 02:23:23</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/opinion/2012/03/19/19putterman/</browser_link><header>Ron Paul's libertarian values admirable but won't win </header><teaser>Though Ron Paul has no chance at securing the Republican nomination, his presence in the race is important. </teaser><images /><id>52978</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline>Mark Putterman</byline><staffline /><section>columns</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;MADRID — As an American student studying abroad in Spain, my daily concerns have more to do with Spanish verb conjugation patterns and the question of whether to have red or white wine with dinner than with the Republican presidential race. And yet, over the past few months I have taken to watching their debates for entertainment. As the old saying goes, after all: Know your enemy.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Somewhere along the way, though, as I made my way through assorted YouTube clips, amid the mess of war mongering, religion-tinged politics and white-affluent-male egos, a strange thing happened. I found myself inexplicably drawn to a certain Ron Paul, congressman, veteran, experienced obstetrician-gynecologist (seriously).&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Oddly charming in his ill-fitting suit jacket, the 76-year-old libertarian is the Rocky Balboa in the race for the Republican nomination — the lovable, quirky underdog. In a race too often categorized by name-calling, misinformation and shouting matches, Paul has distinguished himself with his consistent, informed and articulate debate performances, in spite of the tendency for moderators to blow him off in favor of the so-called front-runners (see Jon Stewart's amusing bit on the subject). In interviews he is knowledgeable, poised and genuinely passionate about the issues. Paul opposes the costly foreign policy of interventionism, vehemently denounces the practice of engaging the American military without a proper declaration of war, is devoted to fighting Wall Street's chokehold on Washington and is passionate (read: obsessed) about reforming the Federal Reserve System. Indeed, there is much about Paul for a liberal to like.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In truth, though, I could never support Ron Paul for president. While his candidacy is refreshing in its contrast to the majority of mainstream conservative values, the informed rationality of some of his more appealing views are, ultimately, overshadowed by his more radical ones. Paul's plan to eliminate the income, capital gains and death taxes eclipses even Herman Cain and his 9-9-9 plan in its utter infeasibility. Meanwhile, his libertarian values are just a bit too, well, libertarian, especially when it comes to his views on gun control, legalization of drugs and his position that the 1964 Civil Rights Act diminished "civil individual liberty."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But it would be too easy to simply dismiss Paul as an out-of-touch radical. In spite of his extreme views, there is something compelling —&amp;#160; something important — about him. In 2008, after losing the Republican nomination to John McCain, Paul defied party leaders by refusing to give McCain his endorsement and to Obama, for that matter. Instead, Paul offered support to Ralph Nader and other third-party candidates and chastised the rigidity of our two-party system as an undemocratic "charade." Paul is right, and in many ways it is this rigidity — where red and blue can never meet — that has led to the paralyzing partisanship that now grips our Congress. Moreover, while other politicians of both parties bend their values to match those of their own party, Paul is nothing if not obstinate in his ideals. In one debate, Paul was asked how social conservatives could support a candidate who would allow for the legalization of marijuana, heroin, prostitution and — God forbid — gay marriage. The question drew laughter from the conservative South Carolina crowd. Yet, Paul's response — that consenting, mature adults have the right to live their own lives without the meddling of a big, baby-sitting government — actually drew applause. In another debate, while his fellow candidates sought to bolster their national security credentials by delivering tough talk regarding sanctions and the possible use of military in preventing Iran from becoming a nuclear power, Paul was the lone voice of reason, comparing such talk to the war propaganda that led to the Iraq war. Paul very passionately voiced his opinion that initiating costly military engagement in the face of trillions of dollars in national debt does little for enhancing national security. &amp;#160; &amp;#160; &amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Paul has no chance at securing the Republican nomination, a fact that he openly admits. Yet, his very presence in the race is important. Paul's refusal to compromise his sometimes extreme beliefs for the sake of political gain is admirable. And by bringing controversial, nontraditional positions to the national stage for debate, Paul brings fresh blood into a race in which the same old issues and the same old rhetoric are being beaten to death. Paul is right in his critique of the current political situation. In a world where politicians too often tell you just what they think you want to hear, Paul is the cranky old man who simply does not give a damn. And that is something important.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 02:22:07</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 01:56:11</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/opinion/2012/03/19/19house/</browser_link><header>N.Y. DREAM Act opens doors to the undocumented</header><teaser>Through the New York DREAM Act, the federal government could provide a brighter future by expanding college and citizenship access to young illegal immigrants.</teaser><images><item><width>1875</width><content_id>52972</content_id><credit>Illustration by Jourdan Enriquez</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/c4/c1/c4c193b92fdf3724bc8b4cd72c26d7e9.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/19/19house/house.jpg</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/4a/a9/4aa9f89bb318f5108785d1c1ba939efe.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/d7/13/d713301ea52a728bf6a6e1ea7ef2d227.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/opinion/2012/03/19/19house/</browser_link><height>2054</height></item></images><id>52972</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/8a/2a/8a2a12df10b3c7e7d30c1e2830cb9d91.jpg</thumb><byline /><staffline /><section>columns</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Immigrants' rights and government leaders in New York, including Mayor Michael Bloomberg, have pushed vocally for a New York state version of late senator Ted Kennedy's proposed-but-never-passed federal Development, Relief and Education for Alien Minors Act. The federal act, as proposed, would have expanded college and citizenship access for ambitious young Americans of good moral character who were brought to the United States illegally as children.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The New York version, however, would not and could not be as far-reaching. The proposal, endorsed by the CUNY and SUNY systems, would allow young illegal immigrants living in New York State to access financial aid and in-state tuition. These students — our peers — are striving to attain higher education. In a world where levels of academic achievement for first- and second-generation immigrants are often stubbornly low, those from disadvantaged groups trying to attain a higher education of the highest quality should be helped along at every possible point.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Blanket denials of financial aid rewards to illegal immigrants only serve to perpetuate historical iniquities. These immigrants are economically discouraged from applying to institutions of higher learning. Such a disadvantage manifests itself in both the job market and, ergo, citizenship status.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;The New York DREAM Act would be a step in the right direction. Expanding access to higher education in our country helps to level out inequalities not of the students' making. Yet, a federal DREAM Act would be far more effective in establishing a framework in which states can work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;Currently, the federal government's lack of such a bill leaves the door open to a gross variety of immigrant-friendly and immigrant-deterrent policies. For example, Texas Governor Rick Perry has championed Texas' DREAM Act, which charges lower tuition rates to some children of illegal aliens than it does to out-of-state American citizens. On the other side of the spectrum, a recent Alabama law requires public school officials to collect data on the number of illegal immigrants enrolling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The New York DREAM Act opens doors previously closed to many first-generation Americans. This motive is in keeping with the ethos of our origins and would rectify our ugly history of prejudice toward these people. That said, this is a matter of national identity as citizenship, and the responsibility should rest on the federal government to reach an acceptable policy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:56:11</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 01:53:02</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/opinion/2012/03/19/19gonzalez/</browser_link><header>Obama plays a game of chess with Iran</header><teaser>As Obama determines how to handle our issues with the Middle East, he plays a chess game where rules must be followed in order to win.</teaser><images /><id>52971</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline>Olivia Gonzalez</byline><staffline /><section>columns</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;It is easy to imagine President Barack Obama behind a fanned deck of cards, plotting his moves against Iran in a poker match. But in this case, the more appropriate analogy is that of a chess game. This is not a bluff-off between two players but rather an infinitely more complicated situation. Obama's rook is pinned by the impending checkmate of a national security threat, and the chess board is riddled with the potential dangers of a move gone wrong. Across from him, the political phantasmagoria of his opponent takes a knight between its fingers and raises it above the board while America and the Middle East hold their breath.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Obama's current red lines leave him cornered: He is either committing himself to a war with Iran or having American credibility shattered by being caught in a bluff. Where the final piece falls will depend on Obama's ability to manage the high-pressure chess match of relations with a nuclear Iran. Like any shrewd international strategist, Obama will have to abide by the rules in the player's handbook in order to win:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Do not underestimate. Assume the opponent will make the move that will cause you the most damage:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The rhetoric sways left and right internationally. While some believe that the actual threat of a nuclear Iran is miniscule, others consider the possibility very serious indeed. If the United States approaches the situation acknowledging Iran's nuclear chops and their willingness to use them, Obama will not find himself blind sided. In this case, the move that would cause the U.S. the most damage would be for Iran to prepare for or carry out a nuclear strike.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Assess the immediate&amp;#160;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and long term threats:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;For the moment, tightening the noose of economic sanctions, and diplomacy are buying the U.S. time. But the more immediate, looming threat on the horizon is Iran's acquisition of nuclear prowess may escalate to a brutal strike. The U.S. red lines have historically evaluated the short-term threat as the development of a nuclear weapon and drawn the line in the sand there. Empty threats were thrown at North Korea and India, but when the line was crossed, our inert reaction revealed our weakness. Historically, bellicose intentions motivated by nuclear power were curbed against red China as well as Pakistan, India and North Korea. So why skip deterrence now?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;It is likely the answer lies in the long-term threat of a nuclear Iran. The U.S. reasonably cannot accept the possibility of a nuclear armament in the hands of an anti-American theocrat. If Iran's nuclear mission goes beyond the goal of protecting itself from an Israel they consider volatile, then we may have a rogue government on our hands — one with the means of selling weaponry to anti-American terrorist groups. From this stems the American fear.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p3"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Look at the whole board:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;The playing field is vast and complicated terrain. The U.S. and Israel differ on the urgency of Iran's nuclear threat; the region is within risk of destabilization if Sunni-Shiite tensions escalate, and the U.S. risks looking like a paper tiger if it does not follow through on its red lines. If Obama's words look hollow to the international community, potential terrorists could be emboldened, and American credibility would be shattered in the eyes of nuclear nations. Israel and Iran justify their nuclear armaments with the belief that they are entitled to protect themselves. But doubling the nuclear power will not make anyone safer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Countries are entitled to protect themselves, but a country with a poor human rights record and a tendency to sponsor terrorism should not be allowed to develop a nuclear weapon. Obama is right in not advocating for war with Iran, but his current red lines may force him into a war that would be the foreign policy checkmate of his presidency.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:53:02</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 01:51:55</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/opinion/2012/03/19/19khedr/</browser_link><header>Diplomacy should trump sanctions in Iran</header><teaser>Past approaches with Iran have fruitlessly been centered around sanctions; diplomacy is the best way to deal with the nuclear issue.</teaser><images /><id>52970</id><thumb>None</thumb><byline>Omar Khedr</byline><staffline /><section>columns</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;As election fever engulfs the United States, Israel and Iran, the question of Iran's nuclear program has become a focal issue. It received heavy emphasis last week when Israeli Prime Minster Netanyahu spoke at the 2012 American Israel Public Affairs Committee policy conference. He described the last decade's diplomatic efforts with Iran as failures. Upon examination, however, it becomes quite evident that serious, sincere and sustained diplomatic efforts have not yet taken place. As a result, the International Atomic Energy Agency and the major participants -— United States, China, Russia, the United Kingdom, France, Germany and Iran -— need to embark on a serious diplomatic initiative.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;As future leaders, we should care about finding a diplomatic solution. Past efforts to engage Iran on its nuclear program have taken a wrong, sanction-centric approach without giving diplomacy its proper due. Sanctions that affect the general population, especially if unilaterally imposed like the current gasoline and financial sanctions, are counter-productive to diplomatic efforts. It sends a threatening message to Iran and makes it harder to build an international coalition to pressure Iran. Furthermore, making hasty demands for regime change and imposing unilateral economic sanctions, as Moshe Ya'Alon, Israel's Strategic Affairs minister calls for, only increases the risk of tensions.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;Diplomacy among parties, especially those with a history of mistrust, requires an investment in trust and time. How can we expect the Iranians to trust our quest for dialogue, let alone our proposals, when our own diplomats are forbidden to talk with them in regional conferences? At the same time, Iran's lack of transparency and sincerity in dealing with the IAEA, a lack of focus in meetings with the P5+1 nations — the five permanent members of the United Nations Security Council and Germany — and its own domestic political problems complicates the issue of trust further. As Mohammed ElBaradei, former IAEA director and Nobel Peace Prize laureate said, there are three core concerns holding both sides back: "trust, transparency and future intentions." &amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;Therefore, keeping lines of communication open is critical. In remarks made before retiring, Admiral Mike Mullen, former chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff said, "Even in the darkest days of the Cold War, we had links to the Soviet Union. We are not talking to Iran, so we don't understand each other. If something happens … there will be miscalculation which would be extremely dangerous in that part of the world."&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s4"&gt;With this in mind, the establishment of consulates and liaisons in Tehran, Isfahan and Qom — three of Iran's most important cities — is necessary. This initiative would demonstrate U.S. mutual respect to Iran (a goodwill gesture to reassure the Iranians), allow for communications to be established with the fractured Iranian political players (power in Iran is divided among several players) and provide our political leaders with more accurate information (instead of relying on second-hand information as we did in Iraq). &amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s4"&gt;While diplomatic initiatives should be given an honest chance to resolve Iran's nuclear program, it is important not to remain idle about the other crucial regional factors. Resolving these important issues can reinforce the U.S. negotiating position when dealing with the Iranian nuclear file.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s4"&gt;German foreign minister Guido Westerwelle said this week at the U.N., "An international coalition for peace and enforcement in the region can only last for the long term, through a resolution in the Israeli-Palestinian issue."&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s4"&gt;Keeping in mind that there is no one model of democracy, the developments of the Arab Spring has already brought Tunisia, Libya and Egypt into the democratic club of nations. Therefore, the impetus and the importance of resolving the Israeli-Palestinian issue should be given the highest priority.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;For the good of everyone, the U.S. should avoid engaging in polemics with Iran. Instead, it should focus its attention in seriously restarting the Israeli-Palestinian negotiations, extending support for the new Arab democracies and starting serious diplomatic efforts with Iran to resolve its nuclear program.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:51:55</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 05:25:13</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/sports/2012/03/19/19wgolf/</browser_link><header>Women's golf starts spring season in Georgia</header><teaser>The women's golf team competed in one of the toughest Division III events, the Jekyll Island Collegiate Invitational, held in Georgia this weekend.</teaser><images><item><width>618</width><content_id>52969</content_id><credit>Courtesy of NYU Athletics</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/0d/a5/0da5e7d682660c218b69b1a8be4e7077.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/19/19wgolf/03-19-wgolf.jpeg</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/df/30/df30eef8d7679b744b7667e90b68b1f5.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/16/3a/163ad75fa6c9b47271d3dcc44bcfcd83.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/sports/2012/03/19/19wgolf/</browser_link><height>318</height></item></images><id>52969</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/68/ff/68ffc038a183a288950b4a27a848fe08.jpg</thumb><byline>Cole Riley</byline><staffline /><section>sports</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;NYU's women's golf team traveled to Georgia to take part in the Jekyll Island Collegiate Invitational hosted by Oglethorpe University from March 16 to 18.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The Violets finished in 15th place with a total score of 1,207. Top-ranked and 14-time defending National Champion Methodist University pulled out a first-place finish with a score of 942.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Regarded as one of Division III's toughest events, the Invitational took place at the prestigious par-72 Indian Mound on Jekyll Island. Some of the country's strongest squads made up the 21-team field, including Methodist University, No. 4 Centre College and No. 10 Illinois Wesleyan University.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;On March 16, the Violets shot a 347 that landed them in 16th place. Sophomore co-captain Kristina Shalhoup shot a seven-over par, 79 in the round, placing her in a tie for tenth place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Freshman Deanna Lee Jia Yi finished her day with a season-low of 87, placing her in a tie for 57th place. Senior co-captain Meaghan Kenny finished 73rd after shooting an 89.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;After one day of play, Methodist University was in first place with a score of 311.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;NYU improved in the second day of competition, scoring a 341.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;Shalhoup shot an 81 on the round and dropped to 16th place in the standings. Junior Jiye Kim improved with a score of 83, nine strokes better than her first-round score of 92.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Kenny scored a second-round score of 92, dropping to a tie for 87th place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Despite Shalhoup's improved play on Saturday, the Violets entered Sunday stuck in 16th place still.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;In the final round, the Violets shot for a collective score of 339, their highest score over the three days of competition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Yi finished tied for 60th with a score of 84 on March 18. The Violets top finisher for the weekend was Shalhoup who tied for 22nd with a three-day total of 242.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Methodist University's junior Jennifer Sullivan grabbed first-place individual honors with a weekend tally of 224, five strokes ahead of second.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;NYU will return to the links at the McDaniel Spring Invitational in Abbottstown, Pa., held from March 31 to April 1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:50:30</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 01:47:56</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/sports/2012/03/19/19trackfield/</browser_link><header>NYU trio races at UMiami Invitational</header><teaser>Men's Track and Field sent three members to Hurricane Invitational at Coral Gables.</teaser><images><item><width>1024</width><content_id>52967</content_id><credit>Courtesy of NYU Athletics</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/0f/86/0f860ae3785470f1f34d20eda8523369.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/19/19trackfield/03-19-track.jpeg</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/7e/64/7e641017dcab382e16a80e539b566a17.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/ba/25/ba259fd8cc378b1b84e89e8016374a74.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/sports/2012/03/19/19trackfield/</browser_link><height>1536</height></item></images><id>52967</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/54/0e/540e0f06ebd08f334b0776fb3ffd3578.jpg</thumb><byline>Amy Rose Ramapuram</byline><staffline /><section>sports</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The NYU track and field teams kicked off the spring season in Florida with three members of the men's team competing in the University of Miami's Hurricane Invitational in Coral Gables.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Junior Brian Broderick, sophomore Michael Caracappa and freshman Kevin Hill represented NYU in the event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Broderick finished in third place in the 3,000-meter steeplechase with a time of 10:12.81.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;In the 5,000-meter run, Caracappa and Hill grabbed 12th place and 17th place, respectively. Caracappa finished the race with an impressive time of 16:30.63 while Hill also ran a strong race, completing the run with a time of 17:53.44.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Though only three members ran, both the men's and women's track and field teams found themselves in Florida over NYU's spring break. The Violets were preparing for the upcoming outdoor spring track and field season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"Everything about spring break was great, and I feel like the focus was on point for everyone on the team," sophomore team member Gilson Cortes said. "Hopefully we can keep up the hard work during the rest of the semester."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The men's and women's teams will return to competition at the North Carolina State Raleigh Relays from March 30 to 31.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:47:56</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 01:45:16</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/sports/2012/03/19/19mvball/</browser_link><header>Men's volleyball earns two wins at weekend tournament</header><teaser>Men's volleyball emerges with a 17-6 record after the Carthage/Milwaukee School of Engineering Tournament this weekend. </teaser><images><item><width>1862</width><content_id>52968</content_id><credit>File photo by David Lin</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/17/85/178594da7c7d0e2b5dd5eb2ce2085738.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/19/19mvball/03-19-mvball.jpg</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/01/31/01313f65ca86fba0438cb98775d6f27b.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/7d/60/7d60a8b9961149faf0b074435c207617.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/sports/2012/03/19/19mvball/</browser_link><height>2798</height></item></images><id>52968</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/11/b5/11b5f043c530ccf45ebca56d987b8b46.jpg</thumb><byline>Sara Levy</byline><staffline /><section>sports</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;NYU men's volleyball won two out of four matches at the Carthage College/Milwaukee School of Engineering Tournament in Milwaukee on March 16 and 17. Carthage, Juniata College, MSOE and Eastern Mennonite University — all non-conference competitors — also participated in the tournament during the weekend.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;On March 16 the Violets defeated the Eastern Mennonite Royals in straight sets. Junior outside hitter Taylor Fauntleroy and sophomore middle blocker Nick Capriccio both reached double digits in kills with 13 and 11, respectively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;For their second match of the weekend, NYU played against Carthage, currently ranked third nationally by the American Volleyball Coaches Association. The Carthage Red Men ended the Violets' four-match win streak, winning all three sets by scores of 25-14, 25-20 and 25-22. Carthage's sophomore setter Connor Wexter recorded a match-high 35 assists while sophomore setter Connor Mortland led the Violets with 29 assists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;The Violets also fell to the fourth-ranked Juniata Eagles in four sets. After losing the&amp;#160;first set 25-19, the Eagles bounced back to win the last three sets 25-19, 26-24 and 25-23. Fauntleroy finished with an astonishing 20 kills and freshman opposite Matthew MacDonald recorded a career-high 16 kills in NYU's second consecutive loss.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Matt is continuing to develop into a top-level opposite," head coach Jose Pina said. "Against the two top level teams, Carthage and Juniata, we did not play our best and our lack of height in the middle was exploited by both. The other two, EMU and MSOE, were weaker opponents and we defeated them without much trepidation."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s3"&gt;NYU earned their second victory of the tournament in three sets versus the MSOE Raiders. The Violets are now 2-5 on the road and 17-6 overall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s4"&gt;Men's volleyball will return to Coles Sports Center to play against Stevens Institute of Technology, a fellow member of the United Volleyball Conference. The match will begin at 7 p.m. on Wednesday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:43:07</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 01:41:03</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/life/2012/03/19/19martin/</browser_link><header>Gallatin alumnus brings his beats off-Broadway</header><teaser>Gallatin alumnus Mark Martin demonstrates his beatboxing in an off-broadway a capella production called "Voca People." </teaser><images><item><width>1328</width><content_id>52964</content_id><credit>Jonathan Tan</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/34/c9/34c97c8a82a17636bf1682ca198df754.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/19/19martin/03-19-martin-jonathan-tan.jpg</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/63/76/63761c700de68c94fb02f8f4bd111117.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/37/ec/37ec5340d33f820525c3904b1b85ddcb.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/life/2012/03/19/19martin/</browser_link><height>1753</height></item></images><id>52964</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/c9/f1/c9f100bb70ee5651c9d9a37dbc3d7e0a.jpg</thumb><byline>Michelle Lee</byline><staffline /><section>features</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;In a new off-Broadway musical, eight talented a cappella singers — clad in white — play extraterrestrials who crash their musically powered spaceship onto Earth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Gallatin alumnus and beatboxer Mark Martin, 23, is on the international cast of this world-renowned vocal percussion show, "Voca People." He plays Captain Beat On, leader of his people. The show features a cappella mash-ups and medleys of songs by diverse figures including Madonna, Queen and Mozart.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;Originally from West Hartford, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Conn., Martin began vocally emulating instrumental sounds at a young age.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"Growing up, when boys are playing around, they make funny sounds like guns and spaceships," Martin said. "When I was little, I used to do stuff like that, and the first thing I beatboxed was the D.J. scratch in Will Smith's song, 'Gettin' Jiggy Wit It.'"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;As an NYU student, Martin sang and beatboxed in the a cappella group APC Rhythm.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;While studying music business in the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education and Human Development his sophomore year, he discovered the beatboxing scene in New York. Martin attended hip-hop cyphers, jams in Union Square Park and underground shows in Brooklyn.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Martin later changed his major to Language of Persuasion in the Gallatin School of Individualized Study to pursue a theoretical approach to language, linguistics and phonetics.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;While Martin did not initially intend to pursue beatboxing as a career, his passion flourished as he grew closer to the tight-knit beatboxing community, which led him to the "Voca People" auditions last summer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"When you're auditioning, you're competing," Martin said. "But when I walked in [to the "Voca People" auditions], there were 20-something beatboxers, all high-fiving. Everyone was so excited to be in a room with that many beatboxers. You could barely tell we were competing against each other."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Tiago Grade, 27, a renowned beatboxer from Portugal, plays Scratcher, the youngest brother of Martin's character and his beatboxing partner in the musical. &amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"I remember one moment when [Martin] cracked up and was in the center of the show, and he burped while he was performing, but the timing was very good in the beatboxing," Grade said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Martin's most memorable moment with beatboxing occurred when a young man standing beside him started rapping as Martin beatboxed while waiting for a subway train.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"Having conversations with people without ever saying a word to them are some of my favorite memories with beatboxing," Martin said. "It's fun because you can really immerse yourself to the point where you feel like you're just talking to someone. When their face lights up, they get it."&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;When he is not performing on stage, Martin jams with other musicians, experiments with electronic sound and volunteers at the Lavelle School for the Blind, where he works with students on recognizing sounds he produces.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"I feel beatboxing could be integral in education," Martin said. "I think it allows for a vocabulary of comprehension that I think we need this day and age in technology to truly describe what you hear."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:41:03</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 02:41:49</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/19/19hawks/</browser_link><header>Hawk Cam welcomes new hawk, returns with educational focus</header><teaser>After its shutdown last August, the Hawk Cam returned last week with Bobby's new mate and an educational focus. </teaser><images><item><width>592</width><content_id>52974</content_id><credit>via Livestream</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/90/21/90219dd9af2d406d6920de1dc375bdf7.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/19/19hawks/03-19-hawks.png</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/4d/7f/4d7f2e0e7dc8f870a1acf0a2d55ff67a.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/00/86/00861cb3e5e2c0a598d519f2e658b39f.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/19/19hawks/</browser_link><height>332</height></item></images><id>52974</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/7b/a4/7ba41ebab3a31d97c2fc2e74d9e72be4.jpg</thumb><byline>Eric Benson</byline><staffline /><section>campus</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The Hawk Cam at Bobst Library officially returned for its second season last Monday. Perched on the 12th floor of Bobst, the live webcam featured on The New York Times website is now focused on two red-tailed hawks, Bobby and Rosie, who call the ledge outside of NYU President John Sexton's window home.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hawk Cam was first launched last spring to stream live footage of Bobby and his mate Violet, who died in late December due to heart complications. Millions of online viewers watched the couple birth and raise their young up until the cameras shutdown after both hawks flew away in August last year.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;This year, NYU spokesman John Beckman has proposed a more expansive educational role of the Hawk Cam by partnering with the New York City Audubon, a grassroots community that works to protect wild birds in New York City.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"As an educational institution, we thought it would be beneficial if there was more of an educational aspect to the Hawk Cam from the outset than was the case last year," Beckman said. "New York City Audubon is in a great position to help educate us all about hawks, about how to think about wildlife in general and in urban settings and to give us insights into what's going on in the nest."&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Featured on the City Room section of The Times website, Hawk Cam sports both its own blog and chatroom to accompany the live feed.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Times reporter Emily Rueb, who updates the blog, expressed City Room's anticipation for this new season of bird watching.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"We are excited to welcome back the Hawk Cam feature that built a lively community last year," Rueb said. "A partnership with New York City Audubon will also increase the educational components of the feature this season with a new question and answer session with readers. The camera will remain in place as long as the birds do."&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Susan Elbin, ornithologist and New York City Audubon director of conservation and science, has worked in the field of behavioral ecology and conservation for more than 25 years and is currently answering readers' questions regarding the hawks.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"Red-tailed hawks typically build their nests in trees," Elbin said on the City Room website. "But when trees are not available, they will build nests on cliff faces. In New York City, our cliff faces are tall buildings with window ledges and setbacks." &amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;In addition to expert commentary, Hawk Cam may soon be scheduled to partner with local schools for further educational opportunities.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"As to working it into educational programs, that would be up to NYU faculty to decide for themselves, though it would be great," Beckman said. "We may look to see whether there is an opportunity to work with local schools in some way, but that's very preliminary."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;LSP freshman Justyna Michaelik said the cam is a great way to interact with nature without harming it.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;"All in all, I think it's really cool how they set up the hawk cam since it gives us a view into the life of animals that we don't see on a day to day basis," Michaelik said.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:35:12</published></article><article><subheader /><updated>2012-03-19 01:33:46</updated><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/19/19park/</browser_link><header>Fences come down in Washington Square Park</header><teaser>Washington Square Park reopened the Chess Plaza in the southwest corner earlier this month. </teaser><images><item><width>3532</width><content_id>52973</content_id><credit>David Lin</credit><t800_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/17/8b/178bcea98a910e012f16b21b6993d017.jpg</t800_url><caption /><url>http://s3.nyunews.com/articles/images/2012/3/19/19park/03-19-park1-david-lin.jpg</url><t_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/a0/8c/a08c734a387b34e30c6d419a7254eef1.jpg</t_url><t300_url>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/c4/2b/c42bd35fd267d6852ab46401a881c38e.jpg</t300_url><browser_link>http://nyunews.com/news/2012/03/19/19park/</browser_link><height>2832</height></item></images><id>52973</id><thumb>http://s3.nyunews.com/cache/a6/b9/a6b907d5cddbfc4992eba4467c04f663.jpg</thumb><byline>Emily Yang</byline><staffline /><section>city-state</section><comments>True</comments><content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Fences that had once surrounded the Chess Plaza in the southwest corner of Washington Square Park came down on March 7.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;According to Philip Abramson of the New York City Department of Parks and Recreation, the opened space contains a new plaza with 18 chess tables, perimeter fencing, light poles and greenery.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The reconstruction of the park began in the winter of 2007 and has now completed two out of three phases. A new playground and more benches and sitting area opened in the fall of 2011.&amp;#160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"Our goal was to create a renewed sense of space, with a design that restored and upgraded the significant features that make Washington Square Park an iconic destination for New Yorkers and visitors alike," Abramson said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Phase III was expected to be completed by winter 2011. But Abramson said the next phase will begin this spring and last for one year. When completed, it will include a large, renovated dog run and park house with a public restroom and space for the maintenance staff.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Cathryn Swan, creator of the Washington Square Park Blog, said the opening of the new area will bring positive results to the community. But she said this phase is long overdue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"Even though the central plaza where the chess tables are has been reduced a lot in size, this section is an important part of the park," Swan said.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"The southern end has a different feeling, maybe because people are coming from Bleecker and MacDougal where there is a lot going on," she added. "So it'll be nice to have a flow again through the park from there."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Long-time WSP visitor Vince Marchese, 70, said the fences took away from the beauty of the park for too long.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"I would say it looks like an improvement of about 50 percent," Marchese said. "It's a nice place to go to, where things happen all the time." &amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;He said other aspects of the park, including the cleanliness of the existing public restrooms and how often the fountain is turned on, have room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Ellie Halevi, a Tisch freshman and Hayden resident, said the area is now less of an eyesore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"I really like it because it's more open, and it means more places to sit and hangout," she said. "It's really nice because it's natural. We no longer have to look at those big ugly fences."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Until May of 2007, WSP was used as a site for NYU's Commencement Exercises. NYU spokesman John Beckman previously told WSN that the university decided not to return to the park because the renovation led to space constraints.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Beckman said Commencement will continue to take place in Yankee stadium.&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;"Though Commencement at the park was a happy tradition for us, Yankee Stadium has worked out great," he said. "It's permitted us to distribute more tickets for guests [and] family members. When we held commencement in the park, we gave only two guest tickets to each graduate."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><published>2012-03-19 01:33:46</published></article></objects>